ANDROID DEVELOPER · SOFTWARE ENGINEER

A-6, 543, East Kazipara, Mirpur-1216, Dhaka, Bangladesh

□ (+880) 1781-106123 | 💌 i4idrhine@gmail.com | 🖸 IronBlossom | 😩 IronBlossom | 🕲 iron\_blossom | 🗖 IshtiaqMahmood\_Amin

"The true delight is in the finding out rather than in the knowing."

# **Summary** \_

Current Android/React Native Developer at Offshore Software Development company Adaptive Enterprise Limited. Analytical and detail oriented programmer specialized in android development, socket programming and both Object-oriented & Functional programming. A reader, teamworker with steller communication skill who loves Linux, android kernel customization and enjoys tweaking the development environment to its efficiency. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks and learning new technologies and tools when needed.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

### **Adaptive Enterprise Limited**

Dhaka, Bangladesh

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Dec. 2014 - Present

- Developed, supervised and currently maintaining more than seven of NAPCO Security Technologies biggest state of the art apps to manage home security, home automation, video cameras on Android and React Native utilizing Socket Programming(TCP and UDP), Serial port communication (NDK), H.264 video decoding, Bluetooth LE(Low Energy), IPC, AIDL, Google Vision api, Realm for Android etc.
- Implemented an in-house stock exchange analysis app with seamless UX/UI maintaining the Material Design guidelines with tools like MPAndroidChart, Realm for Android.
- Designed and developing a React Native app, that aggregates several reputated government/non-government banks, to make a secured payment rail in the national e-commerce field under DOER.

Cloudwell Limited Dhaka, Bangladesh

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Aug. 2013 - Dec. 2014

- Developed easy-to-use Android apps for the startup, facilitating Paywell's Payment infrastructure from Paywell Services app to in-house applications e.g. Paywell Distributor/Dealer/Collector/Territory Officer app.
- Provisioned backend developers with Servlet +php/Java bridge +Quartz Job Scheduler, by building an app that acts as tiny sms server for TeleTalk REB Bill Payment.
- Java Desktop application (jdk1.6+JavaFX) that pushes sms utilizing SilverStreet sms gateway.
- Worked with Telpo and partially developed Paywell application (with the provided SDK on Embedded-C) on 3 different embedded subsystem POS terminals (TPS300, KMY801B, MIL300)

AnnaNovas IT Dhaka, Bangladesh

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (ANDROID)

Oct. 2011 - Jun. 2013

- Built several apps using REST api, sqlite, custom views/controls, Google Maps API (v1), FCM/GCM(then Google C2DM) etc from ground up.
- Developed 3 inbuilt system apps and the launcher app that executes Linux shell commands for Polaroid Kids Tablet.

# Professional Projects \_\_\_\_\_

## iBridge

# Android+NDK+Socket Comm+IPC +Digest Auth +Realm for Android +Google Vision api

- NAPCO's state-of-the-art security/access control app for intrusion detection, fire alarms, IoT available in Wireless(local & remote) and panel-wired IBR-TOUCH tablet versions.
- Smart Z-Wave™ device automation of indoor and outdoor lights, dimmers, thermostats, locks with scene creation, triggered events & scheds.
- Integrated top branded panel's keypad like ADT®/Honeywell®, DSC®.

iLock Android+Bluetooth LE

• NAPCO Alarm Lock division's smartphone Bluetooth LE solution for unlocking(/locking for Canadian market) proprietary Trilogy®Networx™ ArchiTech™ Series Designer Access Control Locks from any smart device without the need to carry cumbersome ID cards or keys.

## Virtual Keypad & StarLink

#### Android+OkHttn+Socket Comm+IPC

- Virtual Keypad Conventional keypad screen and keypad-programming for renowned security keypad manufacturer e.g. ADT®/Honeywell®, DSC®.
- StarLink Universal intrusion alarm reporting mobile solution with Arming/Disarming capabilities on panels.

#### Polaroid Kids Tablet 2

#### Android with custom UI controllers+Media api

- Kids Vids Proprietary app with age control that streams kids friendly videos from YouTube.
- Kids Start The Launcher app of the tablet with a feature of restricting apps.
- Kids Cam Proprietary app for taking picture and shooting video with built-in fun filters.
- Music Player Audio player app with custom visualizer.
- DJ Studio A little DJ app for kids with fun sounds and beats.
- · Best design and innovation award winner of CES2013. Featured in Engadget, USA TODAY, Digital Trends.

**Paywell Services** Android+Glide

· Designed for retailers or store owners that want to sell mobile airtime and various utility bills of Bangladesh.

#### **Android Development**

## Maps api(v1)+Instagram api+Realm for Android+MJPEG+MPAndroidChart

- OneOrchard OneOrchard brings you a whole different online experience as you use the app along Orchard Road.
- Beer Price Get updated prices, selections, locations and rating from over 3,000 bars in Scandinavia. Both price and selection can easily be updated thorugh the in-app report function.
- Singapore Chinese Orchestra (SCO) Official app for Singapore's only professional Chinese orchestra.
- My Collection Develop for the people who has great passions on regarding there collected Coin, Stamps and Sports Cards.
- MyiSeeVideo iSeeVideo app for Napco's video services for ISEE series cameras.
- CSE (In-house) Chittagong Stock Exchange analysis app with animated Line chart and Bar chart.
- Akij BR (In-house) Akij sales representative person's app for market survey.
- Paywell Distributor, Dealer, Collector, Mobile airtime, Territory Officer (In-house) 5 apps satisfying significant aspects of Paywell's bussiness model, distributor-to-dealer-to-retailer, mobile territory manager.

**React Native Development** Redux+Redux-Saga

- DoerPay Currently under development, aggregated payment solution app.
- iLock Currently under development, NAPCO's Bluetooth LE solution app, redoing in React Native.

# Education

## AUST(Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Apr. 2007 - Sep. 2011

· Completed graduation with CGPA 2.97 from CSE Dept.

# **Extracurricular Activity**

#### PoApper (Developers' Network of POSTECH)

Pohang, S.Korea

CORE MEMBER & PRESIDENT AT 2013

Jun. 2010 - Jun. 2017

- · Reformed the society focusing on software engineering and building network on and off campus.
- · Proposed various marketing and network activities to raise awareness.

# PLUS (Laboratory for UNIX Security in POSTECH)

Pohang, S.Korea Sep. 2010 - Oct. 2011

MEMBER

- · Gained expertise in hacking & security areas, especially about internal of operating system based on UNIX and several exploit techniques.
- Participated on several hacking competition and won a good award.
- Conducted periodic security checks on overall IT system as a member of POSTECH CERT.
- Conducted penetration testing commissioned by national agency and corporation.

NOVEMBER 30, 2018